Photography has been my passion
لطالما كان التصوير هو شفغي المطلق
ever since I was old enough to pick up a camera,
منذ حين كان في مقدوري حمل آلة التصوير
but today I want to share with you
ولكن اليوم أريد أن اشارككم
the 15 most treasured photos of mine,
بأعز 15 صورة على قلبي
and I didn't take any of them.
ولكني لم ألتقط أياً من تلك الصور
There were no art directors, no stylists,
ولم يستخدم في إخراجها أي مخرجين فنيين أو مصممي أزياء
no chance for reshoots, not even any regard for lighting.
او إعادة تصوير .. ولا حتى أي نوع من الإضاءة
In fact, most of them were taken by random tourists.
في الحقيقة معظم هذه الصور ألتقطت بواسطة سواح غرباء
My story begins
ان قصتي تبدأ
when I was in New York City for a speaking engagement,
عندما كنت في نيويورك لأجل ملتقى حوار
and my wife took this picture of me holding my daughter
وقد التقطت زوجتي هذه الصورة لي وانا أحمل طفلتنا
on her first birthday. We're on the corner of 57th and 5th.
في عيد ميلادها الأول .. عند تقاطع شارع 57 و 5
We happened to be back in New York exactly a year later,
من قبيل المصادفة كنا في العام الذي تلى ذاك في ذات الفترة في نيويورك أيضاً
so we decided to take the same picture.
لذا قررنا أن نلتقط ذات الصورة
Well you can see where this is going.
يمكنكم توقع سير القصة الآن
Approaching my daughter's third birthday,
عندما إقتربنا من عيد ميلاد طفلتي الثالث
my wife said, "Hey, why don't you take Sabina back to New York
قالت لي زوجتي .. لماذا لا تأخذ سابينا إلى نيويورك
and make it a father-daughter trip, and continue the ritual?"
وتقوموا برحلة سوية فقط للأب والإبنة لكي تعيدوا ذلك الطقس - طقس التصوير -
This is when we started asking passing tourists to take the picture.
وهنا بدأت أطلب من السواح العابرون أمامنا مساعدتنا في إلتقاط تلك الصور
You know, it's remarkable how universal
كما تعلمون كم هو مثير جداً التصرف
the gesture is of handing your camera to a total stranger.
في تمرير آلة التصوير لغريب كلياً لكي يلتقط لك صورة
No one's ever refused, and luckily no one's ever run off with our camera.
لم يرفض أحد مطلقاً التقاط الصورة .. ومن حسن الحظ لم يجري أحد أيضاً بآلة التصوير بعيداً
Back then, we had no idea how much this trip would change our lives.
في حينها لم نكن نعلم كم يمكن لهذا الطقس وتلك الرحلات أن تغير من حياتنا
It's really become sacred to us.
لقد غدت مقدسة بالنسبة لنا
This one was taken just weeks after 9/11,
هذه الصورة التقطت بعد اسابيع من احداث 9\11
and I found myself trying to explain what had happened that day
ووجدت نفسي حينها مضطراً لكي أفسر لطفلتي ماحدث
in ways a five-year-old could understand.
على نحو تستطيع إبنة 5 اعوام استيعابه
So these photos are far more than proxies
إن الصور أكثر بكثير من كونها
for a single moment, or even a specific trip.
تخلد لحظة ما أو رحلة ما
They're also ways for us to freeze time
انها وسيلة أيضاً لإيقاف الزمن
for one week in October
لمدة أسبوع في كل عام في شهر أكتوبر
and reflect on our times
لكي ننظر إلى أنفسنا و إلى ما قمنا به
and how we change from year to year,
و ما هي التغيرات التي طرأت علينا في العام المنصرم
and not just physically, but in every way.
ليست التغيرات المادية والجسمانية فحسب ولكن كل التغيرات
Because while we take the same photo,
لانه عندما كنا نأخذ نفس الصورة كل عام
our perspectives change,
كانت مفاهيمنا تختلف
and she reaches new milestones,
وكانت طفلتي تنمو وتصل مراحل عمرية جديدة
and I get to see life through her eyes,
وكنت استطيع رؤية الحياة من خلال عينيها
and how she interacts with and sees everything.
وكيف كانت تتفاعل و ترى العالم من حولها
This very focused time we get to spend together
إن هذا الوقت المخصص لنا الذي كنا نقضيه سوية
is something we cherish and anticipate the entire year.
هو في الحقيقة ما نعتز و ننتظره طيلة العام
Recently, on one trip, we were walking,
مؤخراً عندما كنا في رحلتنا و كنا نسير سوية
and she stops dead in her tracks,
تجمدت في موقعها
and she points to a red awning of the doll store
وأشارت إلى مظلة حمراء في متجر دمى
that she loved when she was little
كانت تحبها كثيرا حينما كانت صغيرة
on our earlier trips.
في رحلاتنا الأولى
And she describes to me the feeling she felt
ووصف لي شعورها حينها
as a five-year-old standing in that exact spot.
كما لو كانت إبنة خمسة أعوام في ذات المكان
She said she remembers her heart bursting out of her chest
قالت لي كيف انها تتذكر تسارع دقات قلبها
when she saw that place for the very first time
حينما رأت ذلك المكان للمرة الأولى
nine years earlier.
منذ تسع سنوات
And now what she's looking at in New York
والان نحن نبحث لها عن جامعة في ولاية
are colleges,
نيويورك
because she's determined to go to school in New York.
لانها عزمت على الدخول الى احدى جامعات الولاية
And it hit me: One of the most important things
وقد بدر الى ذهني : واحدة من الامور المهمة جداً
we all make are memories.
على اعتبار أننا جميعاً نصنع الذكريات
So I want to share the idea of taking an active role
لذا اريد أن اتشارك معكم بفكرة متعلقة بالعمل الفعال
in consciously creating memories.
في نسق صناعة وعي الذكريات
I don't know about you, but aside from these 15 shots,
لا أريد أن احكم عليكم .. ولكن بالنسبة لي تلك الصور ال15
I'm not in many of the family photos.
فأنا لست من محبين إلتقاط الصور العائلية ولا أظهر في معظمها
I'm always the one taking the picture.
فأنا دوماً من يلتقط الصور
So I want to encourage everyone today
لذا أريد أن أشجع الجميع اليوم
to get in the shot,
لكي يقفوا أمام آلة التصوير لكي يظهروا في كل الصور
and don't hesitate to go up to someone and ask,
ولا تتردوا مطلقاً في ان تطلبوا من أي شخص من حولكم
"Will you take our picture?"
" هلا إلتقط لي هذه الصورة من فضلك ؟ "
Thank you. (Applause)
شكراً جزيلا ً لكم ( تصفيق )